Guide to the Julio Elizalde Papers [Guía a los escritos de Julio Elizalde], 1973-2007 LATINAMER.2013.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Writings, 1972-2007; I.
  - Writings, November-December 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Nota, Para: Servicios de Inteligencia del Navy [Note, To: Intelligence Services of the Navy], 7 de diciembre, 1985 [December 7, 1985]; 13.; 1 page
    - Nota [Note], 14 de diciembre, 1985 [December 14, 1985]; 14.; 1 page
    - Nota, Para: Servicios de Inteligencia del Navy [Note, To: Intelligence Services of the Navy], 16 de diciembre, 1985 [December 16, 1985]; 15.; 1 page
    - Nota, Para: Servicios de Inteligencia del Navy [Note, To: Intelligence Services of the Navy], 17 de diciembre, 1985 [December 17, 1985]; 16.; 1 page
    - Nota, Para: Servicios de Inteligencia del Navy [Note, To: Intelligence Services of the Navy], 18 de diciembre, 1985 [December 18, 1985]; 17.; 1 page
    - Un mensaje urgente, Para: Servicios de Inteligencia del Navy [An Urgent Message, To: Intelligence Services of the Navy], 24 de diciembre, 1985 [December 24, 1985]; 18.; 4 pages
  - Writings, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Reflexiones: Teóricos del Army, tácticos y estrategias de los marines orientadores políticos de la Air Force, Para: Servicios de Inteligencia del Navy [Reflections: Theories of the Army, Tactics and Strategies of the Marine Political Counselors of the Air Force, To: Intelligence Services of the Navy], 1 de enero, 1986 [January 1, 1986]; 1.; 5 pages
    - Un breve mensaje extremadamente importante, Para: División Política [An extremely important brief message, To: Political Division], 13 de enero, 1986 [January 13, 1986]; 2.; 2 pages
    - Respuesta a un ejecutivo de la Agencia Central de Inteligencia (C.I.A.) [Response to an executive of the Central Intelligence Agency (C.I.A.)], 20 de enero, 1986 [January 20, 1986]; 3.; 5 pages
    - Un mensaje a la División Política [A Message to the Political Division], 26 de enero, 1986 [January 26, 1986]; 4.; 3 pages
    - Reflexiones [Reflections], 30 de enero, 1986 [January 30, 1986]; 5.; 4 pages
    - Otro mensaje, trascendental y decisivo a la División Política [Another Transcendental and Decisive Message to the Political Division], 9 de febrero, 1986 [February 9, 1986]; 6.; 3 pages
    - Un mensaje urgente, Para: Defense Intelligence Agency (D.I.A.) [An Urgent Message, To: Defense Intelligence Agency (D.I.A.)], 30 de marzo, 1986 [March 30, 1986]; 7.; 5 pages
    - Notas (Para ser añadidas al Mensaje Elevado en la mañana de hoy, domingo 30 de marzo, 1986) [Notes (To be added to the Message Raised in the morning of today, Sunday, March 30, 1986)], 30 de marzo, 1986 [March 30, 1986]; 8.; 3 pages
    - Mensajes dramáticos: En un proceso histórico de naturaleza decisiva [Dramatic Messages: In a Historic Process of Decisive Nature], 7 de abril, 1986 [April 7, 1986]; 9.; 4 pages
    - Reflexiones (Para ser añadidas al Mensaje Urgente al Army, Elevado en la mañana de hoy, viernes 18 de abril, 1986) [Reflections (To be added to the Urgent Message to the Army, Raised in the morning of today, Friday, April 18, 1986)], 18 de abril, 1986 [April 18, 1986]; 10.; 3 pages
    - Reflexiones (Para ser añadidas al Mensaje Elevado en la mañana de hoy al Army) [Reflections (To be added to the Message Raised in the morning of today to the Army)], 18 de abril, 1986 [April 18, 1986]; 11.; 2 pages
    - Un mensaje especial a la División Política [A Special Message to the Political Division], 21 de abril, 1986 [April 21, 1986]; 12.; 2 pages
    - Un mensaje a The New York Times: All the News That's Fit to Print [A Message to The New York Times: All the News That's Fit to Print], 22 de abril, 1986 [April 22, 1986]; 13.; 1 page
    - Mensajes especiales a los Teóricos del Army, Segunda parte [Special Messages to the Theorists of the Army, Second part], 24 de julio, 1986 [July 24, 1986]; 14.; 5 pages
    - Para ser añadido al mensaje elevado en la tarde de hoy a los teóricos del Army [To Be Added to the Message Raised Today in the Afternoon to the Theorists of the Army], 27 de julio, 1986 [July 27, 1986]; 15.; 4 pages
    - Una muy severa, severísima denuncia ante la División Criminal del Buró Federal de Investigaciones [A very, very severe denouncement of the Criminal Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigations], 13 de agosto, 1986 [August 13, 1986]; 16.; 3 pages
    - Un mensaje a la División Política [A Message to the Political Division], 17 de noviembre, 1986 [November 17, 1986]; 17.; 4 pages
    - Un mensaje dramático a las Fuerzas Armadas Americanas en una hora histórica decisiva [A Dramatic Message to the American Armed Forces in a Decisive Historic Hour], 21 de noviembre, 1986 [November 21, 1986]; 18.; 4 pages
    - Mensajes políticos dramáticos en un proceso histórico decisivo, Para: Fuerzas Armadas de los Estados Unidos [Dramatic Political Messages in a Decisive Historic Process, To: Armed Forces of the United States], 22 de noviembre, 1986 [November 22, 1986]; 19.; 3 pages
    - Reflexiones, To: Fuerzas Armadas Americanas [Reflections, To: American Armed Forces], 25 de noviembre, 1986 [November 25, 1986]; 20.; 5 pages
    - Segundo mensaje al Gen. Carl E. Vuono, Army Chief of Staff [Second Message to the General Carl E. Vuono, Army Chief of Staff], 25 de noviembre, 1987 [November 25, 1987]; 21.
    - Análisis: Insistencia en un tema capital, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Analysis: Insistence on a Capital Issue, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 26 de noviembre, 1986 [November 26, 1986]; 22.; 2 pages
    - Nota personal, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Personal Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 27 de noviembre, 1986 [November 27, 1986]; 23.; 1 page
    - Un mensaje político en un proceso histórico de naturaleza decisiva, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [A Political Message in a Historical Process of Decisive Nature, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 3 de diciembre, 1986 [December 3, 1986]; 24.; 3 pages
  - Writings, January-July 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Análisis: Ayer Stalin a Roosevelt, hoy Gorbachev a Reagan, el Kremlin vuelve a engañar a la Casa Blanca, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Analysis: Yesterday Stalin to Roosevelt, Today Gorbachev to Reagan, Kremlin returns to fool the White House, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 1 de enero, 1987 [January 1, 1987]; 1.; 7 pages
    - Mensajes dramáticos en un proceso histórico de naturaleza decisiva: Ronald Reagan debe de abandonar la Casa Blanca, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Dramatic Messages in a Historic Process of Decisive Nature: Ronald Reagan should abandon the White House, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 29 de enero, 1987 [January 29, 1987]; 2.; 4 pages
    - Nota: Para ser añadida al mensaje "Una queja más amarga que la hiel", enviado al mediodía de hoy [Note: To Be Added to the Message "A complaint more bitter than bile", Sent Today in the Afternoon], 3 de febrero, 1987 [February 3, 1987]; 3.; 3 pages
    - Un segundo mensaje al Japón [A Second Message to Japan], 11 de febrero, 1987 [February 11, 1987]; 4.; 4 pages
    - Mensajes trascendentales en un proceso histórico de naturaleza decisiva, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Transcendental Messages in a Historic Process of Decisive Nature, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 14 de marzo, 1987 [March 14, 1987]; 5.; 2 pages
    - Un mensaje urgente, Para: U.S. Armed Forces, División Política [An Urgent Message, To: U.S. Armed Forces, Political Division], 3 de abril, 1987 [April 3, 1987]; 6.; 4 pages
    - Mensaje urgente #8, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Urgent Message #8, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 23 de abril, 1987 [April 23, 1987]; 7.; 4 pages
    - Mensaje urgente #11, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Urgent Message #11, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 30 de abril, 1987 [April 30, 1987]; 8.; 3 pages
    - Mensaje urgente #12, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Urgent Message #12, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 7 de mayo, 1987 [May 7, 1987]; 9.; 1 page
    - Mensaje urgente #13, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Urgent Message #13, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 8 de mayo, 1987 [May 8, 1987]; 10.; 3 pages
    - Mensaje urgente #18, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Urgent Message #18, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 26 de mayo, 1987 [May 26, 1987]; 11.
    - Crisis #22 and #23 [Crisis #22 and #23], 12 de junio a 15 de junio, 1987 [June 12 - June 15, 1987]; 12.; 2 pages
    - Crisis #23, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Crisis #23, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 13 de junio, 1987 [June 13, 1987]; 13.; 3 pages
    - Mensaje especial #2 al muy honorable leadership de U.S. Armed Forces [Special Message #2 to the Honorable Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces], 21 de junio, 1987 [June 21, 1987]; 14.; 2 pages
    - Crisis en su clímax, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Crisis in Its Climax, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 22 de junio, 1987 [June 22, 1987]; 15.; 1 page
    - La crisis en su clímax, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Crisis in Its Climax, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 23 de junio, 1987 [June 23, 1987]; 16.; 2 pages
    - Epilogo [Epilogue], 28 de junio, 1987 [June 28, 1987]; 17.; 1 page
    - Crisis #29, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Crisis #29, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 29 de junio, 1987 [June 29, 1987]; 18.; 2 pages
    - Análisis: ¿Cuál es la verdadera misión del general John W. Vessey en su visita a Hanoi? [Analysis: Which is the true mission of the General John W. Vessey in his visit to Hanoi?], 5 de julio, 1987 [July 5, 1987]; 19.; 4 pages
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 6 de julio, 1987; 20.; 1 page
    - Un mensaje desesperado a la "Dirección Teórica" del Army [A Desperate Message to the "Theoretical Direction" of the Army], 12 de julio, 1987 [July 12, 1987]; 21.; 4 pages
    - Crisis #36: Las apariencias afirman que, muy posiblemente, es inevitable una confrontación muy ruda con el Buró Federal de Investigaciones (F.B.I.) [Crisis #36: The looks confirm that, very possibly, a rough confrontation with the Federal Bureau of Investigations is inevitable], 14 de julio, 1987 [July 14, 1987]; 22.; 4 pages
    - Crisis #37, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Crisis #37, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 16 de julio, 1987 [July 16, 1987]; 23.; 4 pages
    - Aclaración A: Crisis #37 [Clarification A: Crisis #37], 16 de julio, 1987 [July 16, 1987]; 24.; 2 pages
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 17 de julio, 1987 [July 17, 1987]; 25.; 1 page
    - Mensajes urgentes a U.S. Armed Forces #23 [Urgent Messages to the U.S. Armed Forces #23], 22 de julio, 1987 [July 22, 1987]; 26.; 3 pages
    - Crisis #42, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Crisis #42, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 29 de julio, 1987 [July 29, 1987]; 27.; 2 pages
  - Writings, August-December 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Un mensaje urgente, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [An Urgent Message, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 3 de agosto, 1987 [August 3, 1987]; 1.; 2 pages
    - Para ser añadido al mensaje urgente #5, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [To Be Added to Urgent Message #5, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 11 de agosto, 1987 [August 11, 1987]; 2.; 2 pages
    - Un mensaje muy breve, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [A Very Brief Message, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 26 de agosto, 1987 [August 26, 1987]; 3.; 1 page
    - Un mensaje urgent, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [An Urgent Message, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 27 de agosto, 1987 [August 27, 1987]; 4.; 2 pages
    - Reflexiones, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Reflections, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 1 de septiembre, 1987 [September 1, 1987]; 5.; 3 pages
    - Reflexiones, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Reflections, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 2 de septiembre, 1987 [September 2, 1987]; 6.; 3 pages
    - Reflexiones, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Reflections, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 4 de septiembre, 1987 [September 4, 1987]; 7.; 3 pages
    - Otro grito de angustia: ¡Yo no puedo más! [Another Cry of Anguish: I can't anymore!], 11 de septiembre, 1987 [September 11, 1987]; 8.; 3 pages
    - Nota analitica: La unica formula es dejar de leer los periódicos y darle la espalda a los conflictos, nacionales e internacionales. Pero ¿no es una irresponsabilidad hacer eso? ¿Tendría posible perdón el crimen de que cierre yo los ojos y tapone mis oídos? [Analytic Note: The Only Formula is Stop Reading the Newspapers and Turn our Backs to National and International Conflicts. But, is it not an Irresponsibility to Do That? Is there the Possibility to Pardon the Crime that I Close my Eyes and Cork my Ears?], 17 de septiembre, 1987 [September 17, 1987]; 9.; 2 pages
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 17 de septiembre, 1987 [September 17, 1987]; 10.; 1 page
    - Un breve mensaje a la División Política [A Brief Message to the Political Division], 21 de septiembre, 1987 [September 21, 1987]; 11.; 8 pages
    - Nota: Mis reservas han descendido de los $20 [Note: My savings have descended below #20], 14 de octubre, 1987 [October 14, 1987]; 12.; 2 pages
    - Un mensaje muy especial a U.S. Armed Forces: Si le sucede algo a Monette, el suceso me heriría irreparablemente [A Very Special Message to the U.S. Armed Forces: If anything happens to Monette, the incident would irreparably hurt me], 11 de octubre, 1987 [October 11, 1987]; 13.; 2 pages
    - Cuatro reflexiones: exclusivamente cuatro, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Four Reflections: Exclusively Four, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 17 de octubre, 1987 [October 17, 1987]; 14.; 3 pages
    - Nota analítica [Analytical Note], 4 de noviembre, 1987 [November 4, 1987]; 15.; 1 page
    - Un mensaje urgente a la República Popular China [An Urgent Message to the People's Republic of China], 12 de noviembre, 1987 [November 12, 1987]; 16.; 3 pages
    - Un mensaje al General Carl E. Vuono, Army Chief of Staff [A Message to the General Carl E. Vuono, Army Chief of Staff], 24 de noviembre, 1987 [November 24, 1987]; 17.; 2 pages
    - Desde la cima del drama mundial: Un caso obvio de alta traición [At the Heights of World Conflict: An Obvious Case of High Treason], 16 de diciembre, 1987 [December 16, 1987]; 18.; 6 pages
    - Desde la cima del drama mundial: La página más negra en la historia de la raza blanca [At the Heights of World Conflict: The Blackest Page in the History of the White Race], 18 de diciembre, 1987 [December 18, 1987]; 19.; 5 pages
    - Reflexiones (Muro de Berlín), Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Reflections (Berlin Wall), To: U.S. Armed Forces], 19 de diciembre, 1987 [December 19, 1987]; 20.; 2 pages
    - Reflexiones, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Reflections, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 21 de diciembre, 1987 [December 21, 1987]; 21.; 1 page
    - Reflexiones, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Reflections, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 26 de diciembre, 1987 [December 26, 1987]; 22.; 2 pages
    - Análisis político: Fracaso de un sistema y enigmática posición del Presidente de los Estados Unidos [Political Analysis: Failure of a System and Enigmatic Position of the President of the United States], 27 de diciembre, 1987 [December 27, 1987]; 23.; 2 pages
    - Un mensaje especial a U.S. Armed Forces [A Special Message to U.S. Armed Forces], 31 de diciembre, 1987 [December 31, 1987]; 24.; 3 pages
  - Writings, January-May 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - S. O. S.: El army no tiene otra alternativa que intervenir, muy enérgicamente, ahora, right now! [S. O. S.: The Army Does Not Have Another Alternative But to Intervene, Very Energetically, Now, Right Now!], 7 de enero, 1988 [January 7, 1988]; 1.; 4 pages
    - Análisis: Otro escándalo en la conspiración contra Occidente [Analysis: Another Scandal in Conspiracy Against the West], 8 de enero, 1988 [January 8, 1988]; 2.; 6 pages
    - Nota: The Hour of the Truth [Note: The Hour of the Truth], 8 de enero, 1988 [January 8, 1988]; 3.; 2 pages
    - Una meditación teórica-política: Es la idea de la Ley la que se halla en crisis [A Theoretical-Political Contemplation: It Is the Idea of Law that Finds Itself in Crisis], 9 de enero, 1988 [January 9, 1988]; 4.; 4 pages
    - Meditaciones socio-políticas [Socio-political Contemplations], 10 de enero, 1988 [January 10, 1988]; 5.; 3 pages
    - Nota: No hay mucha diferencia entre el lenguaje de Gorbachev y el del general Sergei M. Shtemenko [Note: There is not much Difference between the Language of Gorbachev and that of General Sergei M. Shtemenko], 10 de enero, 1988 [January 10, 1988]; 6.; 1 page
    - Nota: Al leadership [Note: To the Leadership], 11 de enero, 1988 [January 11, 1988]; 7.; 1 page
    - Nota: Es posible que esté planteada una situación de amenaza personal [Note: It is Possible that a Situation of Personal Threat is Posed], 11 de enero, 1988 [January 11, 1988]; 8.; 1 page
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 13 de enero, 1988 [January 13, 1988]; 9.; 1 page
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 22 de enero, 1988 [January 22, 1988]; 10.; 1 page
    - Un breve mensaje: Si U.S. Armed Forces no actúa, no tiene sentido mi lucha [A Brief Message: If the U.S. Armed Forces Does Not Take Action, My Struggle Does Not Make Sense], 27 de enero, 1988 [January 27, 1988]; 11.; 2 pages
    - Nota analitica: Mi colapse, muy probable por razones económicas, podría establecer las condiciones que precipitarían la tragedia [Analytical Note: My Collapse, Very Likely for Economic Reasons, Might Establish the Conditions that Would Precipitate the Tragedy], 29 de enero, 1988 [January 29, 1988]; 12.; 5 pages
    - Reflexiones, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Reflections, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 1 de febrero, 1988 [February 1, 1988]; 13.; 2 pages
    - Nota analítica: U.S. Armed Forces, ¿cómo es posible que no comprenda la gravedad extrema de la situación? [Analytical Note: U.S. Armed Forces, How is it Possible to Not Comprehend the Extreme Severity of the Situation?], 24 de febrero, 1988 [February 24, 1988]; 14.; 3 pages
    - Dos reflexiones: exclusivamente dos (Con un micro-epílogo en homenaje al Almirante Crowe) [Two Reflections: Exclusively Two (With a Micro-epilogue in Homage to Admiral Crowe)], 25 de febrero, 1988 [February 25, 1988]; 15.; 6 pages
    - Mini-análisis dividido en incisos [Mini-analysis Divided in Sections], 29 de febrero, 1988 [February 29, 1988]; 16.; 3 pages
    - Nota: El colapso [Note: The Collapse], 6 de marzo, 1988 [March 6, 1988]; 17.; 2 pages
    - Un mensaje especial al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces y a los organismos responsabilizados con la defensa de los Estados Unidos (Dividido en incisos) [A Special Message to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces and Agencies Responsible for the Defense of the United States (Divided in Sections)], 16 de marzo, 1988 [March 16, 1988]; 18.; 4 pages
    - Crisis #11, Para: U.S. Armed Forces (Dividido en incisos) [Crisis #11, To: U.S. Armed Forces (Divided in sections)], 17 de marzo, 1988 [March 17, 1988]; 19.; 1 page
    - Crisis #15: Que China se responsabilice con el trabajo [Crisis #15: That China Take Charge of the Work], 24 de marzo, 1988 [March 24, 1988]; 20.; 1 page
    - Nota analítica: La moral como fuerza histórica [Analytical Note: Moral as a Historic Force], 7 de abril, 1988 [April 7, 1988]; 21.; 3 pages
    - Mensaje especial #9 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces: Momentos decisivos [Special Message #9 to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces: Decisive Moments], 11 de abril, 1988 [April 11, 1988]; 22.; 3 pages
    - Mensaje especial #10 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces: Momentos decisivos [Special Message #10 to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces: Decisive Moments], 12 de abril, 1988 [April 12, 1988]; 23.; 3 pages
    - Mensaje especial #12 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces [Special Message #12 to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces], 18 de abril, 1988 [April 18, 1988]; 24.; 4 pages
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 19 de abril, 1988 [April 19, 1988]; 25.; 1 page
    - Mensaje especial #13 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces [Special Message #13 to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces], 21 de abril, 1988 [April 21, 1988]; 26.; 2 pages
    - Mensaje especial #14 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces [Special Message #14 to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces], 25 de abril, 1988 [April 25, 1988]; 27.; 4 pages
    - Mensaje especial #2 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces (Dividido en incisos) [Special Message #w to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces (Divided in sections)], 27 de abril, 1988 [April 27, 1988]; 28.; 3 pages
    - Crisis, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Crisis, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 9 de mayo, 1988 [May 9, 1988]; 29.; 2 pages
    - Epilogo [Epilogue], 12 de mayo, 1988 [May 12, 1988]; 30.; 1 page
    - Mensaje super trascendental #6 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces (Dividido en incisos) [Super Transcendental Message #6 to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces (Divided in Sections)], 15 de mayo, 1988 [May 15, 1988]; 31.; 4 pages
    - Mensaje especial #18 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces divido en incisos [Special Message #18 to the Leadership of U.S. Armed Forces Divided in Sections], 16 de mayo, 1988 [May 16, 1988]; 32.; 3 pages
    - Análisis: Horas decisivas, Un mensaje a la República Popular China [Analysis: Decisive Hours, A Message to the People's Republic of China], 17 de mayo, 1988 [May 17, 1988]; 33.; 3 pages
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 18 de mayo, 1988 [May 18, 1988]; 34.; 1 page
    - Mensaje especial #18 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces divido en incisos [Special Message #18 to the Leadership of U.S. Armed Forces divided in sections], 19 de mayo, 1988 [May 19, 1988]; 35.; 2 pages
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 22 de mayo, 1988 [May 22, 1988]; 36.; 1 page
    - Nota super especial al leadership: Una sola pero super especial [Super Special Note to the Leadership: Just One But Super Special], 26 de mayo, 1988 [May 26, 1988]; 37.; 1 page
    - Mensaje especial #22 al leadership de U.S. Armed Forces [Special Message #22 to the Leadership of the U.S. Armed Forces], 28 de mayo, 1988 [May 28, 1988]; 38.; 1 page
    - Nota urgente, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Urgent Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 29 de mayo, 1988 [May 29, 1988]; 39.; 3 pages
  - Writings, June-December 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Nota, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 4 de junio, 1988 [June 4, 1988]; 1.; 1 page
    - Desde la cima del drama mundial: Alta traición, Segunda parte [At the Heights of World Drama: High Treason, Second Part], 4 de junio, 1988 [June 4, 1988]; 2.; 7 pages
    - Análisis: Dos páginas de oro en el libro relativo a mis servicios al país [Analysis: Two Pages of Gold in the Book Related to my Services to the Country], 5 de junio, 1988 [June 5, 1988]; 3.; 3 pages
    - Crisis #23, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Crisis #23, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 13 de junio, 1988 [June 13, 1988]; 4.; 3 pages
    - Nota urgente, Para: U.S. Armed Forces [Urgent Note, To: U.S. Armed Forces], 10 de junio, 1988 [June 10, 1988]; 5.; 2 pages
    - Mensaje super trascendental #2 al leadership de General Dynamic Corp., Boeing Co., McDonnell Corp. [Super Transcendental Message #2 to the Leadership of General Dynamic Corp., Boeing Co., McDonnell Corp.], 22 de junio, 1988 [June 22, 1988]; 6.; 3 pages
    - Nota #2, Para: General Dynamic Corp., Boeing Co., McDonnell Corp. [Note #2, To: To: General Dynamic Corp., Boeing Co., McDonnell Corp.], 1 de julio, 1988 [July 1, 1988]; 7.; 1 page
    - Crisis #34: Breves reflexiones, divididas en incisos [Crisis #34: Brief Reflections, Divided in Sections], 7 de julio, 1987 [July 7, 1987]; 8.; 3 pages
    - Mensaje final #3 al leadership de General Dynamic Corp., Boeing Co., McDonnell Corp. (Dividido en incisos) [Final Message #3 to the Leadership of General Dynamic Corp., Boeing Co., McDonnell Corp. (Divided in sections)], 18 de julio, 1988 [July 18, 1988]; 9.; 2 pages
    - Observaciones (Para ser añadidas al Mensaje Especial elevado en la mañana de hoy y dirigido al leadership de General Dynamic, Boeing y McDonnell) [Observations (To be added to the Special Message raised today in the morning and addressed to the Leadership of General Dynamic, Boeing, and McDonnell)], 24 de junio, 1988 [June 24, 1988]; 10.; 2 pages